state.sd.us 2005-12-11

# State of South Dakota Privacy Policy

**State of South Dakota Web Site Privacy Statement  
** The privacy, confidence, and trust of individuals who visit the State of  South Dakota web site are important to us. No personal information is collected at this site unless provided voluntarily by an individual while participating in an activity that asks for the information.

**Collection of Information  
**   The State only collects the personal information that is necessary to provide the information or services requested by an individual. "Personal information" refers to any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual who is the subject of the information. This is the same information that an individual might provide when visiting a government office and includes such items as an individual’s name, address, or phone number. We also collect statistical information that helps us understand how people are using the web site so we can continually improve our services. The information collected is not associated with any specific individual and no attempt is made to profile individuals who browse the web site. You may be asked to participate in surveys at this site. Participation is optional, and the choice to participate or not to participate will have no effect on your ability to use other features of the site. 

**Use of Information  
**   The State uses the collected information to respond appropriately to requests. This may be to respond directly to you or to improve the web site. E-mail or other information requests sent to the State web site may be maintained or forwarded to the appropriate agencies in order to respond to the request. Survey information is used for the purpose designated in the survey. 

**Retention of Information  
**   Records needed to support State program functions are retained, managed, and accessible in record-keeping or filing systems in accordance with established records disposition authorizations approved by the State’s Public Records Commission. Records transmitted to this site will be identified, managed, protected, and retained as long as they are needed to meet historical, administrative, fiscal, or legal requirements. 

**Cookies  
**   Any web page or application at this site may use cookies. Cookies are short and simple text files that are stored on a user’s computer hard drive by web sites. They are used to keep track of and store information so the user does not have to supply the information multiple times. The information that is collected through cookies at this site is handled in the same manner as other information collected here. You can configure your web browser to refuse cookies or to notify you when a web site attempts to send you a cookie. You can also check your hard drive for cookie files and delete them from your computer. 

**Web Site Security  
**   The State of  South Dakota is committed to the security of the information that is either available from or collected by this web site. The State has taken multiple steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. 

**Links to Other Sites  
**   This web site has links to many other web sites. These include links to web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. The State of  South Dakota is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these sites and suggests you review their privacy statements. 

**Contact Information  
**   The State welcomes comments regarding this privacy statement. Please convey any questions or concerns to: 

Bureau of Information and Telecommunications: (605) 773-3416.  E-mail: [ Service.Direct@state.sd.us](mailto:Service.Direct@state.sd.us?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Question/Concern)
